KOFI OBRASI OCRAN

+233546107464, +233501366297, ocran.obrasi@gmail.com, Portolio, GitHub, Twitter, LinkedIn, Technical Blog P.O. Box 378, AGONA, SWEDRU

Summary

I am a passionate Engineer who understands that technology is a growth and business enabler, leveling the field for economic growth, independent of location and limited resources. I have worked with a consulting firm over the years building websites for various clients. I have worked extensively on various datasets; wrangling and visually presenting my findings even as I hone my data science skills.

Experience

Software Developer – EK-BRANDCONSULT – October, 2018 to Now

- I built a <u>Flight Search and Booking Engine</u> with Amadeus API.
- My team and I built and shipped the company's marketing application (Syde Hassle). It currently has more than 1000 registered users and I maintain the software and make feature updates.
- I reduced the time used to deploy WordPress sites to DigitalOcean server used by the company by 90% using a bash script.
- I develop and deploy both dynamic and static websites for Clients in the Real Estate, Travel and Tours, Hospital and Ecommerce industries.
- My team and I built and maintain the <u>E-commerce platform</u> on the company's clients' portal.

Open Source Contributor - HANGAR - August, 2019

• I submitted a PR to implement the Theme Switcher and Light Theme (Mode) for the User Interface.

Freelance Software Developer – January, 2015 to October 2018

- I promoted the online presence of small companies to help market their products and services by developing and launching websites for them.
 Multivew Designs
- I set up custom email for the clients with Zoho mail.
- I built a dashboard; <u>Peg Dashboard</u> for customer transaction management.

Data Analysis Projects – Udacity Data Analyst Nanodegree

- Explore Weather Trends: I compared global temperature trends with the temperature recorded in Accra, Ghana.
- Analysis of A/B Test Results: I analyzed the resulting data from an AB test
 by an ecommerce shop to decide whether they should go ahead with
 rolling out the new landing page.
- <u>Investigate TMDb Movie Dataset</u>: I set out to investigate the TMDb movie dataset to answer some questions such as the top revenue movies from 1960 to 2015, the yearly revenue change, the actor/actress who was featured most in the top 20 movies, etc.
- Wrangle and Analyze Data: I gathered, assessed, cleaned and visually presented some findings from tweets gathered from the <u>WeRateDogs</u> twitter page.
- Communicate Data Findings: I did exploratory analysis on the Loans Dataset from Prosper to find the factors that influence the Loan Status, Interest Rates and the Prosper Score. I found out that most of the Loans were used for Debt Consolidation which projects a cycle of taking Loans to pay off other Loans. I presented my findings in a way that can be easily appreciated by non-technical eyes.

Technical Skills Languages & Libraries: JavaScript (ReactJS, VueJS) and Python (Flask), Pandas,

NumPy, Matplotlib, Jupyter Notebooks **Databases & Serverless**: MySQL, Firebase

APIs: REST and GraphQI

Platforms & Version Control: Git, Linux, Circleci

Education & Certifications

Data Analyst Nanodegree

Udacity, November 2019 to June 2020

BSc. Telecommunications Engineering

KWAME NKRUMAH UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY, KUMASI, GHANA

2017

Competencies and

Strengths

- I'm an effective team player
- I possess strong analytical and numerical skills
- I have a good reception of criticisms and even negative feedback.

References

Available on Request